aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
New Finishing Flaming Sword Art
불꽃의 신 필살검
Space Beast Man Wildie
Appears
은하 수인 와일디 등장
Alien found!
우주인 발견!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어!
Fire Blaster!
파이어 블래스터!
Eat this! Star Burn!
받아라, 스타 번!
No need for help! It's enough by myself!
도와줄 필요 없어
나 혼자서도 충분하다구!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체(火炎合體)!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!
Jet Fire Storm!
제트 파이어 스톰!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!
Use me!
날 사용해라!
Alright! This will make me even stronger furthermore!
좋았어, 물 만난 물고기(鬼に金棒)란 말은 이런걸 두고 하는 거지!
Here it goes!
간다!
You're getting in the way?
멋대로 뛰어들기냐?
He should be alright with Lio Sword!
라이오 소드가 있으니, 괜찮겠죠
Eat this!
받아라!
Fire Lio Sword!
파이어 라이오 소드!
-What?!
-Fire Dagwon!
-아니?!
-파이어 다그온!
Now! Run away!
지금이다, 도망쳐라!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!
En, there's no use feeling down all the time!
엔, 마냥 꿍해 있어도 소용없다구
That's right. Get a grip!
그래요, 기운 내세요
I'm not feeling down!
꿍해 있는게 아니야
I didn't lose to that guy yet.
난 아직 그녀석에게 진게 아니야
I will do it next time...
다음번엔 반드시...
No matter how much you try, the result will be same.
몇번을 해도 결과는 마찬가지다
En. I will give you an advice.
엔, 이것만은 충고해 두지
Dagwon definitely has a power with infinite possibilities.
확실히 다그온의 힘에는 무한한 가능성이 숨겨져 있다
But being able to truly use that ability or not depends on how you do.
하지만 그 능력을 발휘할 수 있을지 어떨지는 어디까지나 본인 하기 나름이야
What do you mean?
그게 무슨 뜻이지?
You cannot use Lio Sword flawlessly yet!
넌 아직 완전하게 라이오 소드를 구사하지 못해
In this rate, instead of becoming stronger, you're wasting resources!
지금 상태론 물 만난 물고기는 커녕, 돼지목에 진주(猫に小判)!
It means that it's totally useless!
아무짝에 쓸모 없다는 말이다!
What?!
뭐야?!
Don't make me laugh!
까불지 말라구!
Not yet!
아직이다!
How's that, En?
어떤가, 엔?
I hope you realized at least a bit.
조금은 깨달았겠지?
Shut up! Dammit!
시끄러! 제기랄~!
En!
엔!
Leave him alone!
내버려둬!
Kai...
카이...
To him of now, comforting won't do anything!
지금의 녀석에게 위로 따윈 역효과야
He has to realize by himself. No, we must make him realize by himself.
혼자서 해결하게 해야해 아니, 혼자서 해결하지 않으면 안돼
Since we can't assume that the alien will keep being inactive like now
그 우주인이 이대로 얌전히 있으리라곤 생각할 수 없으니까 말이다
What a cold guy!
쳇! 냉정한 녀석이구만
En.
엔...
Damn!
줴기라~알!
Know this! I will train myself and become stronger!
두고봐라! 특훈해서 강해져 보일테다!
You'll see!
두고보라구!
Damn! What was that?
젠장... 뭐야?
Y- you!
너, 너는...
What are you doing, Ryu?!
무슨 짓이야, 류?
You bastard!
이쉐이!
First, you have to be able to use that wooden sword with your bare body.
우선 맨몸으로 그 목도를 자유자재로 다룰 수 있어야 한다
When you can, maybe with Lio Sword too...
그렇게 되면, 어쩌면 라이오 소드도...
Everything depends on how you do it.
모든건, 너 하기 나름이다
Damn Ryu! That was an useless interruption!
류 녀석, 쓸데없는 참견이나 해대고 말야
Alright, if you insist, I'll do sword play or something!
좋아, 칼부림(ちゃんばら尾)인지 뭔지, 하면 되잖아!
I guess he's not in the school.
그녀석, 학교에는 없는 모양이군
Let's believe in En.
엔을 믿읍시다
But still...
하지만 말야...
Kai should be thinking the same too.
분명, 카이도 그렇게 생각하고 있을 겁니다
Damn! I'm not finished yet!
젠장! 아직이다!
I'll do this as much as I can!
할 수 있을 때까지 몇번이고 해주마!
It seems that the alien is raging in the various places on the Earth.
그 우주인, 세계 각지에서 날뛰고 있는 것 같습니다
Damn! We can't let it do as it wants!
제길! 이대로 녀석 좋을대로 내버려 둘 것 같냐!
Let's go out!
출동하자!
Nope. Even if we don't move, it'll definitely show itself.
아니, 서두르지 않아도 반드시 녀석 쪽에서 나타날 거다
In front of us Dagwon.
우리들 다그온의 앞에 말야
Why didn't he finished Fire Dagwon that time?
녀석은 왜 그때 파이어 다그온을 끝장내지 않은 걸까?
Don't you think it could finish him easily?
충분히 끝장낼 수 있었을 거라고 생각하지 않아?
That's right...
그러고보니...
To that guy, the battle before was nothing more than an opening to a game.
녀석에게 있어, 그 싸움은 게임의 오프닝에 지나지 않았던 거다
It's going to finish the real game soon.
슬슬 본 게임을 끝내려고 하겠지
That bastard! It looked down on us!
이자식! 우리들을 얕봤겠다!
Hey.
그만둬
The next battle will be the real battle.
이번에야말로 진정한 싸움이 될 것 같군요
That's what we wished for.
바라던 바다!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Alright! It isn't a problem now!
좋았어! 해냈어!
Yes! I'm a genius!
역시 난 천재라구!
Dammit! Can't I cut a single leaf after all this training?!
제길! 이만큼이나 특훈했는데도 나뭇잎 하나 못 가르는 거냐!
Why is that?!
어째서냐?!
Grandpa!
할아버지
What are you doing in such place?
이런 곳에서 뭐 하시는 게요?
Hello, Daidouji.
여어~ 다이도우지
Did you escape again?
또 땡땡인겐가?
Well, I'm not in a position to say that, though.
뭐, 나도 그런 말 할 입장은 아니지만
Hey, did you escape too?
뭐야, 할아버지도 땡땡이요?
This is my hiding place.
이곳은 나의 비밀기지(隱れ家)란다
I like to spend time alone, apart from the everyday routine.
일상의 잡무에서 벗어나 가끔 혼자서 이렇게 시간을 보내는걸 좋아해서 말야
But it's a secret to the vice principal.
하지만, 교감 선생님껜 비밀이란다
Same for me too!
피차 일반이니까요
Grandpa! If you need manual labor, I'll do the work!
할아버지, 힘 쓰는 일이라면 제가 할게요
Really? It's pretty difficult.
그래 주겠나? 꽤 어렵단다
It's nothing. This is just a wood-chopping.
별 거 아니예요, 장작 패기 쯤이야...
This is weird... This looked so simple!
이상한데... 이런건 간단해 보였는데 말야
It's not a thing that you can do only by power.
그렇게 힘에만 의존해서 하는게 아니라네
-Damn!
-Move.
-젠장~
-비켜 보게
I'll show you how you do it.
내가 본보기를 보여주지
Why I can't do something that you can?
어째서 할아버진 할 수 있고, 난 못하는 거지?
Well, it's simple with some knack.
뭐, 약간의 요령만 터득하면 간단하다네
Knack?
요령?
First, get rid of useless power.
먼저 쓸데없는 힘은 버리고
Aim for the center and when you hit,
중심을 잘 노려서, 맞추는 순간
concentrate your consciousness to the end of the ax.
의식을 도끼 끝에 집중시키는 거라네
Like this.
이런 식으로 말이네
Try again. You'll understand if you keep trying.
해 보게나, 몇번 반복하면 분명 알게 될 거라네
Get rid of useless power and aim for the center.
쓸데없는 힘을 버리고, 중심을 잘 노린다
Like this...
이런 느낌으로...
I see! The point is how I use the power!
그렇군! 요점은 힘의 사용방법이었구나!
Alright! Now I understand!
좋아! 왠지 이해가 가기 시작했다!
You're pretty good at this.
제법 솜씨가 좋구나
It could've been better if your understanding was fast like that.
공부도 그정도로 이해가 빨랐으면 좋겠지만 말이네
I see!
그렇군!
Grandpa! I'm sorry to let you down, but I must leave!
할아버지! 중간에 죄송하지만, 전 이만 갈게요
Thank you!
고마워요!
I did it!
성공이다!
Shin here!
여기는 신!
En! The alien we saw before appeared again!
엔! 일전의 우주인이 또 나타났어!
I see.
그렇군
You bastard! We won't let you do as much as you want!
이놈! 언제까지고 니 멋대로 날뛰게 내버려두진 않는다!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Armor!
다그 아머!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Wing!
다그 윙!
Break Wheel!
브레이크 호일!
Let's do Chaining Fusion!
중련합체다!
Chaining Fusion!
중련합체(重連合體)!
Liner Dagwon!
라이너 다그온!
Liner Blizzard!
라이너 블리자드!
Now, come!
자, 덤벼라!
I'll take care of that guy!
녀석은 내가 맡겠다!
Dag Shadow!
다그 새도우!
Shadow Shuriken!
섀도우 수리검!
Now we'll have one-to-one match!
자, 일대일 승부다!
Armor Buster!
아머 버스터!
We got it!
잡았다!
Eat this!
받아라!
What the?!
아니?!
What the...? Turbo Wheel Cutter!
이건...?
터보 호일 커터!
Wait!
기다려라!
I'll take that guy down!
그녀석은 내가 해치운다!
En!
엔!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체(火炎合體)!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!
Fire Dagwon! Watch out for its eye!
녀석의 눈을 조심해라!
Fire Hold!
파이어 홀드!
Fire Lio Sword!
파이어 라이오 소드!
Good job, Fire Dagwon!
멋지다, 파이어 다그온!
Good afternoon, grandpa!
안녕하슈, 할아버지~
Oh, it's you, Daidouji. Would you like to join the bath too?
다이도우지인가... 어떤가, 자네도 목욕 할텐가?
No, I'm good.
아뇨, 전 됐어요
Actually I'm here to say thanks.
사실은, 잠깐 고맙단 말을 하러 왔어요
What are you talking about?
무슨 일인가?
Well, forget it!
뭐, 신경 끄세요
Just let me help with the fire.
자, 제가 불 때 드릴게요
Could it be that the grandpa is actually someone great?
(혹시, 할아버지는 대단한 사람이 아닐까?)
A person shouldn't be determined on the look, too.
(사람은 겉모습으로 판단하지 말라는 말이 있으니 말야)
He- help me! I'll be cooked!
사- 살려주게! 구이가 되겠어!
Oh, no! I must've put too much woods! I'm sorry!
저런! 장작을 너무 넣었군요! 죄송해요!
This grandpa is just a normal grandpa!
(역시 할아버지는 보통 할아버지군)
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
A powerful space beast, Griffin appeared.
강력한 우주수, 그리핀이 나타났어
We Dagwon can't face him who brought downfall to numerous planets!
수많은 별을 멸망시킨 녀석의 힘은 다그온들도 섣불리 덤비지 못해!
That Griffin started to love Maria.
그런 그리핀이 마리아를 사랑하게 되었어
Griffion! Stop destroying the village!
그리핀! 마을을 파괴하는건 그만둬!
You're simply being controlled!
넌 조종당하고 있을 뿐이라구!
Wake up!
눈을 떠!
Don't make Maria sad!
마리아를 슬프게 하지 마라!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! A Kind Space Beast
다음회 용자지령 다그온
마음씨 착한 우주수
You actually were...
넌... 사실은...!
마음씨 착한 우주수